[{"question":"<p><strong>The locus of a point equidistant from the intersection of lines 3x - 7y + 7 = 0 and 4x - 6y + 1 = 0 is a<\/strong><\/p>","options":["line parallel to 7x+13y+8=0","circle","semicircle","bisector of the line 7x-13y+8=0"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The gradient of the straight line joining the points P(5,-7) and Q(-2,-3) is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1\/2","2\/5","4\/-7","-2\/3"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find dy\/dx if y=cos x<\/strong><\/p>","options":["sinx","-sinx","tanx","-tanx"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The mean of seven numbers is 96. If an eighth number is added, the mean becomes 112. Find the eight number<\/strong><\/p>","options":["126","180","216","224"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The mean of seven numbers is 96. If an eighth number is added, the mean becomes 112. Find the eight number<\/strong><\/p>","options":["126","180","216","224"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the median 2,3,7,3,4,5,8,9,9,4,5,3,4,2,4 and 5<\/strong><\/p>","options":["9","8","7","4"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the range of 4,9,6,3,2,8,10 and 11<\/strong><\/p>","options":["11","9","8","4"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the standard deviation of 2,3,8,10 and 12<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3.9","4.9","5.9","6.9"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Evaluate <sup>n+1<\/sup>C<sub>n-2<\/sub>&nbsp;if n=15<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3630","3360","1120","560"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The cost of renovating a 5m square room is N500. What is the cost of renovating 10m square room?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N1000","N2,500","N2000","N10,000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>The cost of renovating a 5m square room is N500. What is the cost of renovating 10m square room?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N1000","N2,500","N2000","N10,000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the rate of change of the total surface area S of a sphere with respect to its radius<\/strong><\/p>","options":["8&pi;","16&pi;","10&pi;","14&pi;"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Differentiate (cos&theta; +sin&theta;)<sup>2<\/sup> with respect to&nbsp;&theta;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2cos2?","2sin2?","-2cos2?","-2sin2?"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>A binary operation * on the set of rational numbers is defined&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>x * y = (2x + x<sup>3<\/sup> - y<sup>3<\/sup>) \/ (x<sup>2<\/sup> + y<sup>2<\/sup>)&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>find -1*2<\/strong><\/p>","options":["11","-11","8","-8"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the range of values of x for which 7x&gt;3x+4<\/strong><\/p>","options":["x < 7\/4","x > 7\/4","7x < 4","-4x < 7"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Calculate the standard deviation of the following data 7,8,9,10,11,12,13<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2","4","10","11"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>If W is the mode and Z is the median of the following set of numbers 2.4,2.1,1.6,2.6,2.6,3.7,2.1 and 2.6 then (3W, 2Z) is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["(2.6,2.5)","(7.8,5.0)","(2.1,2.5)","(6.2,5.0)"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>A trapezium has two parallel sides of length 6cm and 8cm. If the area is 42cm<sup>2<\/sup>, find the distance between the parallel sides<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6cm","8cm","7cm","5cm"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>In a bag, there are 8 identical balls in terms of size and shape, but 2 are white, 4 are black and 2 are yellow. If<\/strong><br \/><strong>balls are randomly drawn from the bag without<\/strong><br \/><strong>replacement, what is the probability that two cells drawn<\/strong><br \/><strong>from the bag, one is white and the and the other black?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2\/7","6\/7","5\/7","1\/7"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the roots of the equation 6x<sup>2<\/sup>&nbsp;- 13x + 6 = 0<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2\/3, 3\/2","2\/3, -3\/2","-2\/3, -3\/2","2\/3, 3\/2"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>A polynomial in x whose zeros are 2, -1 and -7 is x2+6x2+9x14bx3 &ndash; 6x2+14cx3+6x2 &ndash; 9x14 dx3 &ndash; 6x2 &ndash;<\/strong><br \/><strong>9x+14 6. If y = (91-3x)3. find the value of dy at dx2. x = -2<\/strong><\/p>","options":["378","-441","-378","441"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>If y = (1-3x)<sup>3<\/sup>. find the value of dy\/dx at x = -2<\/strong><\/p>","options":["378","-324","-378","441"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Convert 366 base ten to a binary number<\/strong><\/p>","options":["101110010","-101101110","10110111","-1011000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Given that x = 3, y = -2 and z = -1. Evaluate 3x<sup>2<\/sup>y<sup>2<\/sup>zx<sup>2<\/sup>y<sup>3<\/sup>z<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6776","9787","-7776","-9776"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Two ships A and B left port P on a bearings 0530 and<\/strong><br \/><strong>1130 respectively. If both ships steamed at 80km per<\/strong><br \/><strong>hour, how<\/strong><br \/><strong>far apart were they after 30 minutes?<\/strong><\/p>","options":[".-80km","60km","20km","40km"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>What are the coordinated of the midpoint of the line<\/strong><br \/><strong>joining (-1, 6) and (5, -3)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["(3, 4.5)","(2, 1.5)","(-3, 4.5)","(-2 ,- 1.5)"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Determine <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">2.813 x 1.063<\/span>&nbsp;&nbsp;x 10<sup>-1<\/sup>&nbsp;reducing each number to 2 s.f and leaving the answer in 2s.f.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 5.637&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["0.54","0.0054","0.0056","0.055"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Solve the inequality 2-x &gt; x<sup>2<\/sup>.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["x < 1 or x < -2","x > 2 or x < -1","x < -2 or x > 1","x > 2 or x < -2"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>. Find the minimum value of the function f(0)= 2 ,for 0= 0<\/strong><br \/><strong>=2?3-CosO<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1\/2",".2\/3","2","1"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>A fair coin is tossed ten times. What is the probability of<\/strong><br \/><strong>getting at least two heads?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["513\/1024","615\/1024","968\/1024","1011\/1024"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>A man bought 220 mangoes at #5x. He sold each for<\/strong><br \/><strong>3x kobo and made a gain of #8. Find the value of x.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2","5","10","6"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Calculate the sum to infinity of 1 + 1\/3&bull;}1\/9-1\/27+<\/strong><\/p>","options":["0.33","0.67","1.5","2,5"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Express tan 22 1 \/2, in the sun! form<\/strong><\/p>","options":["+ v2-2","l-v2","+v2-1",".+v2+l"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>If sin (x-a)=Cos (x+a), then tans is<\/strong><\/p>","options":[".0.8","0.75","1.0","2.8"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>A binary operation x is defined on R, the set of real<\/strong><br \/><strong>numbers by xy = vxy, for all x,y E R. If x*(2*8)=6,find<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2","4","9","10"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>The equation 2x2 + (k + 3) x + 2k = 0 has co-incident<\/strong><br \/><strong>roots. What is the constant k7<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3 or 7","4 or 0","9 or l","9 or l"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>The curve y =2x* + x-2 and the straight line y-2x-1<\/strong><br \/><strong>meet at the points whose x-values are<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1\/2andl","2andl","1\/2andl","2"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the mean deviation of 5, 8, 3,7and 2.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["0","2","5","10"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>The sequence &lsquo;a, -&lsquo;I., &lsquo;I -1\/256 has a terms. Determine<\/strong><br \/><strong>the value of n<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6","7","8","9"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>The volume of two similar solid cubes are729cm3 and<\/strong><br \/><strong>5 12cm3. Find the ratio of their lengths<\/strong><\/p>","options":["4:3","9:7","9:7","9:8"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>In fig C, PR is a diameter, &lt;PRQ=(3x-8), and<\/strong><br \/><strong>&lt;RPQ=(2y-7), Express x in terms of y<\/strong><\/p>","options":["x= 75+ 2y","x= 105 + 3y","x= 105-2y","x = 75- 3y"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the mean deviation of 6,7,8,9, 10<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1.2","1.5","2","8"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Thematrixis2l, 34<\/strong><br \/><strong>If I is the 2x2 unit matrix, then k2 +1 + k is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6 3 1320","9 8 2223","l0 7 2124","1 4 25"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>The line joining (p, 4) and (6, -2) is perpendicular to<\/strong><br \/><strong>the line joining (2,p) and (-1.3).Find p<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6","3","4","0"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>In a regular polygon, each interior angle double its<\/strong><br \/><strong>corresponding exterior angle. Find the number of sides of<\/strong><br \/><strong>the polygon<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3","4","6","8"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>The mean of the numbers 0, x+2+, 3x+6 and4x+8 is<\/strong><br \/><strong>4. Find their mean deviation<\/strong><\/p>","options":["4","3","2","0"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>The average of three numbers is 32<sub>5<\/sub>. If the sum of the numbers is 131<sub>4<\/sub>, find the third number in base 6<\/strong><\/p>","options":["43<sub>6<\/sub>","34<sub>6<\/sub>","23<sub>6<\/sub>","32<sub>6<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Three times the second term plus the seventh term of an AP is equal to the twelfth term. Find the relationship between the first term and the common difference<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3a-2d =0","3a+2d = 0","3a+d = 0","3a-d = 0"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>A fence of 36m is to be built to make three sides of a rectangular compound, the fourth side being a building. Find the possible lengths of the shorter side of the compound if the area enclosed is 160m<sup>2<\/sup><\/strong><\/p>","options":["20m,10m","16m,8m","20m,16m","10m,8m"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find dy\/dx if y = 2x<sup>2<\/sup> - sin2x<\/strong><\/p>","options":["4x+2cosx","4x-2cos2x","4x-4cos2x","4x+4cos2x"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>A bag contains 4x First Bank ATM cards (2x-1), UBA Bank ATM cards and 3(x+1) Zenith Bank ATM cards. If the probability of picking a First Bank ATM is 2\/5; how many UBA Bank ATM cards are in the bag?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3","8","9","20"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Express the product of 0.000128 and 0.00125 in standard form&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1.6x11<sup>-1<\/sup>","1.6x10<sup>-5<\/sup>","1.6x10<sup>-7<\/sup>","1.6x10<sup>-4<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>If(2x-1)+1\/(2x-1)=4, find the value of 4x-4x+1\/(2x-1)<sup>2<\/sup><\/strong><\/p>","options":["19","13","-13","-19"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>A student dropped an object from a building 100m high. If the height of the object object above after t seconds is 100-4.9t<sup>2<\/sup>m. How fast is it falling 3 seconds after it is dropped?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["14.7m\/sec","85.3m\/sec","29.4m\/sec","70.6m\/sec"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>An investor who received N6500.00 as some simple interest rate collected a total amount of N7,800.00 after four years. How much simple interest would he have collected after two years if he had invested N9,000.000?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N1000.00","N10000.00","N650.00","N900.00"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>If the sum of the roots of the equation 2x<sup>2<\/sup> - 5px + 8 =0 is five times the product of the roots, find the value of P<\/strong><\/p>","options":["-8","1\/8","8","-1\/8"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>If log<sub>10<\/sub>4=x, express log(12.5)<sup>3<\/sup> in terms of x&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["4-3x","6x-2","4+3x","4(1-x)"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the area of the region enclosed by the curve y=2-x<sup>2<\/sup> and the line y=-x<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3\/2","9","3","9\/2"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Simplify (log(xy<sup>2<\/sup>) - 2log x + log y\/x<sup>2<\/sup>) \/ (log (y\/x)<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>For 0&lt;x&lt;y<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["-3","3","-1\/3","1\/3"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Simplify (2x<sup>3<\/sup> - x<sup>2<\/sup> - 13x - 6 = 2x + 1) \/ 2x + 1<\/strong><\/p>","options":["(x-2)(x-3)","(x-2)(x+3)","(x+2)(x+3)","(x+2)(x-3)"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>The solution to the simultaneous equation 2x + y = 10 and 4x<sup>2<\/sup> - y<sup>2<\/sup>&nbsp;= 140 is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["x=2, y= -6","x=2, y=6","x=6, y= -2","x=6, y=2"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the equation of the circle which passes through the points (0,0) and (-1,2) and whose center lies on the line y-2x+1=0<\/strong><\/p>","options":["(x-1\/2)<sup>2<\/sup> + (y-2)<sup>2<\/sup> = 25\/4","(x+1\/2)<sup>2<\/sup> + (y+2)<sup>2<\/sup> = 25\/4","(x-2)<sup>2<\/sup> + (y+3\/2)<sup>2<\/sup> = 25\/4","(x+3\/2)<sup>2<\/sup> + (y+3\/2)<sup>2<\/sup> = 25\/4"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Evaluate lim<sub>x-&gt;1<\/sub> (x<sup>2<\/sup>+x-2) \/ (x-1)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["0","3","2","1"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>A student pumps a ball and its volume increases at the rate of n(16-t<sup>2<\/sup>)cm<sup>3<\/sup> per second. If the initial volume is (11n)cm<sup>3<\/sup>, find the volume of the ball after 3 seconds<\/strong><\/p>","options":["28n cm<sup>3<\/sup>","68n cm<sup>3<\/sup>","39n cm<sup>3<\/sup>","50n cm<sup>3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Score&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 0&nbsp; &nbsp;1&nbsp; 2&nbsp; 3&nbsp; 4&nbsp; &nbsp; 5<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>No. of students 24&nbsp; 8&nbsp; 4&nbsp; 6&nbsp; 10&nbsp; 8<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>The distribution above shows the scores of 60 students in a class test. What percentage of the students scored at least 3<\/strong><\/p>","options":["60%","36%","66%","40%"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Subject Biology Chemistry Maths Physics<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Marks&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;95&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;2x+10&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; x&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 75<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>If the total mark obtained by a student is 300, what is the angle corresponding to the mark obtained in chemistry if the information is represented in a pie chart?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["120<sup>o<\/sup>","114<sup>o<\/sup>","48<sup>o<\/sup>","108<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>A basket contains 5 MTN cards, 6 GLO cards, 3 9mobile cards and 3 Airtel cards. What is the probability that the card selected from the basket at random will be MTN or 9mobile cards?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3\/2","3\/4","1\/4","3\/5"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the difference between 1.867551 correct to four significant figures and 1.867551 correct to four decimal places<\/strong><\/p>","options":["5x10<sup>-3<\/sup>","4x10<sup>-4<\/sup>","5xx10<sup>-4<\/sup>","10x10<sup>-3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the range of values of x satisfying the inequalities&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>2x - 5 &lt; 7 and 25 + 2x &gt; 15<\/strong><\/p>","options":["5<x<`-6","5<x<6","6<x<5","6<x<-5"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>If the 8th term of an AP is three times the second term and the sum of the first three terms is 18, find the first term of the A.P<\/strong><\/p>","options":["4","2","3","8"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the sum to infinity of the series 4+3+9\/4+27\/16+...<\/strong><\/p>","options":["16","16\/3","1","8"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the equation of the line which passes through (-2,1) and is perpendicular to the line 4x - 2y + 1 = 0<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2y - x - 4 = 0","2y + x = 0","2y - x = 0","y - 2y - 5 = 0"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>An interest covered a distance of 44cm before reaching a point Q. Calculate POQ<\/strong><\/p>","options":["63<sup>o<\/sup>","12<sup>o<\/sup>","13<sup>o<\/sup>","60<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>The first derivative of y = (2+3x)4 at x = -1 is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["12","-12","4","-4"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>The minimum value of (x) = x<sup>2<\/sup>-4x+5 in the interval(-1,1) is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3","2","4","5"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>A company is to select three different handset phones from five different types of Nokia Brand and two different types of Samsung Brand. In how many ways can the company choose the handset, so as to include at least one Samsung brand?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["15","25","35","45"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"}]